Register of the Gleb Struve Papers 1810-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1810-1985 (Boxes 69-148)
  - Berlin, P. Clippings, 1947-1964 (Folder 14)
  - Bilimovich, Aleksandr, "Great Powers and the World Evil of Communism, a Plea for Joint Action", open letter(?), Oct. 20, 1938 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Bisk, Aleksandr. Clippings, 1939-1973 (Folder 2)
  - Bitsilli, P. Printed matter, scholarly articles, 1929-1948 (Folder 3)
  - Blok, Aleksandr. Printed matter
    - Articles from scholarly journals, includes biographical material, 1924 (Folder 4-5)
    - Clippings from newspapers, 1956-1983 (Folder 6)
  - Boem, Alfred
    - Correspondence between Alfred Boem and Gleb Struve, 1931-1939 (Folder 7)
    - Biography. Short article by Vadim Morkovin, typescript, n.d. (Folder 8)
    - Printed matter, 1931-1937 (Folder 9)
  - Bogatyrev, Konstantin
    - Correspondence of Gleb Struve
      - Bogatyrev, Konstantin. Includes correspondence of his wife Elena Bogatyreva, 1975-1976 (Folder 10)
      - Glade, Henry, 1976 (Folder 11)
      - Will, George, 1976 (Folder 12)
    - Printed matter. Includes clippings and reprints of articles by and about Konstantin Bogatyrev, 1976-1983 (Folder 13)
  - Bol'shukhin, Iurii. Clippings, 1957-1984 (Folder 14)
  - Borman, Arkadii
    - Correspondence between Arkadii Borman and Gleb Struve, 1923-1926, 1947 (Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1967 (Folder 16)
  - Borrow, George
    - Miscellaneous material. Includes handwritten notes by Gleb Struve and bibliographical material, 1940's (Folder 17)
    - Clippings, 1950-1985 (Folder 18)
  - Briusov, Valerii
    - Correspondence of Valerii Briusov
      - "V. Ia. Briusov, pis'ma k F. Sologubu", Ezhegodnik Pushkinskogo Doma, 1973, photocopy (Folder 19)
    - Writings, "Novye techeniia v russkoi poezii. Akmeizm", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 20)
    - Printed matter. Photocopies of miscellaneous articles re Valerii Briusov, n.d. (Folder 21)
  - Brodsky, Iosif
    - Writings. Poetry, typescript copies and clippings, 1965-1970 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Material related to Iosif Brodsky's trial, 1964, typescript and printed matter (Folder 2)
    - Gladstone, William, translator and editor, "The Trial of Joseph Brodsky", produced by BBC, 1965, typescript copy (Folder 3)
    - Clippings from Novoye Russkoe Slovo, 1967-1970 (Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1964 (Folder 5)
  - Bulgakov, Mikhail
    - Writings. "Sobach'e serdtse", galley proof, n.d. (Folder 6)
    - Printed matter
      - Articles from scholarly journals, 1974 (Folder 7)
      - Clippings from newspapers, 1958-1984 (Folder 8)
  - Bulgakov, Sergei. Writings. Copy of article from unidentified Yalta newspaper, Feb. 1920 (Folder 9)
  - Bunin, Ivan
    - Correspondence of Ivan Bunin
      - Struve, Gleb, 1925-1934 (Folder 10)
      - Teffi, photocopies, 1935-1952 (Folder 11)
      - Zaitsev, Kirill, 1925-1926 (Folder 12)
    - Writings, "My Meetings With Tolstoy", galley proof, n.d. (Folder 13)
    - Printed matter
      - Articles from scholarly journals, 1961 (Folder 14)
      - Clippings from newspapers, 1927-1983 (Folder 15-16)
    - Struve, Gleb, miscellaneous handwritten notes, n.d. (Folder 17)
  - California Slavic Studies
    - Correspondence with Gleb Struve, 1960-1976 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Struve, Gleb, critiques of articles submitted, typescript, n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Celan, Paul
    - Correspondence of Gleb Struve
      - Celan, Paul, 1959-1960 (Folder 3)
      - Rais, E.M., 1951-1976 (Folder 4)
      - Struve, Aleksei, typescript excerpts, 1961 (Folder 5)
    - Writings, "Osip Mandelstamm, Gedichte", Die Neue Rundschau, 69, Jahrgang 1958, offprint with holograph notes (Folder 6)
    - Printed matter, Terras, Victor and Weimar, Karl, "Mandelstamm and Celan: Affinities and Echoes", Germano-Slavica, No. 4, Fall 1974, photocopy (Folder 7)
  - Chaianov, Aleksandr. See Kremnev, Ivan
  - Christian Committee For the Defense of Believers' Rights in the U.S.S.R. Documents. Russian texts with English translations, 1977, printed copy (Folder 8)
  - Chekhov, Anton
    - Struve, Gleb. Miscellaneous notes and fragments, handwritten and typescript, n.d. (Folder 9-11)
    - Printed matter
      - Scholarly articles, 1963-1981 (Folder 12)
      - Clippings from emigre newspapers, 1921-1983 (Folder 13)
  - Chukovskii, Kornei
    - Correspondence
      - Shklovskaia, Zinaida. Includes handwritten poem, 1903 (Folder 14)
      - Struve, Gleb, 1962, 1963 (Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1957-1980 (Folder 16)
  - Conference On Soviet Literature, Oxford University, July 1962
    - Biographical notes on paricipants of conference (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Typescript copies of papers delivered by participants
      - Brown, Edward, "The Year of Acquiescence" (Folder 2)
      - Forgues, Pierre, "La Poesie Sovietique Contemporaine" (Folder 3)
      - Frank, Victor, "Boris Pasternak" (Folder 4)
      - Friedberg, Maurice, "Soviet Books, Censors and Readers" (Folder 5)
      - Futrell, Michael, "Boris Pilnyak" (Folder 6)
      - Gibian, George, "Soviet Russian Literature During the Thaw" (Folder 7)
      - Hayward, Max, " Conflict and Change in Soviet Literature" (Folder 8)
      - Herling, Gustav, "Isaac Babel" (Folder 9)
      - Liencourt, Francois de, "Changes and Continuity In Contemporary Soviet Theatre" (Folder 10)
      - Muchnic, Helen, "Literature in the NEP Period" (Folder 11)
      - Reavey, George, "Maxim Gorky" (Folder 12)
      - Tarasova, Natalia, "Tema bogoborchestva v poezii V. Majakovskogo" (Folder 13)
      - Vickery, Walter, "Zhdanovism: 1946-1953" (Folder 14)
      - Wat, Alexander, "Quelques apercus sur les rapports entre la literature et la realite sovietique" (Folder 15)
  - Darov, Anatolii. Clippings, 1968-1985 (Folder 16)
  - Davats, V.
    - Correspondence between V. Davats and Gleb Struve, 1934 (Folder 17)
    - Writings, Pravda o Struve, photocopy of pamphlet, 1934 (Folder 18)
  - Dekhterev, Aleksandr, "Sinii plen", typescript collection of miscellaneous poetry, 1932 (Folder 19)
  - Dioneo (Isaak Shklovskii). Tearsheets of articles, n.d. (Folder 20)
  - Dni, miscellaneous issues, Feb.-March 1926 (Folder 21)
  - Dobuzhinskii, Mstislav
    - Correspondence between Mstislav Dobuzhinskii and Gleb Struve, 1938 (Folder 22)
    - Writings, "O risunkakh Pushkina", typescript draft, 1937 (Folder 23)
  - Dostoevsky, Fedor. Printed matter
    - Clippings from emigre press, 1918-1983 (Folder 24)
    - Articles from scholarly journals, 1923-1983 (Folder 25)
    - Articles from scholarly journals, 1913-1982 (Box 82, Folder 1-3)
  - Ehrenburg, Ilya. Printed matter, 1921-1970 (Folder 4)
  - Eikelovich, Igumen Gennadii
    - Correspondence of Igumen Eikelovich
      - Losskii, Nikolai, 1954-1958 (Folder 5)
      - Panin, Dimitrii, 1976-1978 (Folder 6)
      - Zenkovskii, Fr. Vasilii, 1952 (Folder 7)
    - Writings
      - "Filosofemy i teologumeny", collection of articles, typescript, n.d. (Folder 8)
      - Review of Dimitrii Panin, "Vselennaia glazami sovremennogo cheloveka", typescript, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - Eisner, Aleksei
    - Miscellaneous poetry, printed excerpt, 1928 (Folder 10)
    - Novosil'tsev, Igor', "O poterianykh poetakh", typescript copy, 1976(?) (Folder 11)
  - Eltsova, K. Writings, "Moi vospominaniia, 1917-1918", typescript copy, n.d. See correspondence between Gleb Struve and L. Zurov (Folder 12)
  - "England Through Russian Eyes". Typescript excerpts and clippings, including short articles by Vladimir Weidle and Prince Sviatopolk-Mirskii, 1929-1936 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Ershov, Petr. Clippings, 1951-1954 (Folder 2)
  - Esenin, Sergei
    - Printed matter
      - Articles from scholarly journals, 1967-1975 (Folder 3)
      - Clippings from newspapers, 1934-1983 (Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1967-1976 (Folder 5)
  - Eurasianism. See Petr Savitskii
  - Fadeev, Aleksandr. Miscellaneous printed matter, 1936 (Folder 6)
  - Fedin, Konstantin. Clippings, 1947-1949 (Folder 7)
  - Fedotov, Georgii
    - Correspondence between Georgii Fedotov and Gleb Struve, 1931-1938 (Folder 8)
    - Writings
      - "Russia and Freedom", The Review of Politics, Jan. 1946, printed copy (Folder 9)
      - "Zapad, SSSR i atomnaia bomba", uncut draft of published article with explanatory note by Georgii Fedotov and short introduction by Gleb Struve, typescript, 1946 (Folder 10)
  - Fesenko, Tat'iana. Clippings, 1956-1984 (Folder 11)
  - "Fifty Years of Communism in Russia", Conference at Hoover Institution, Stanford University, 1967. Miscellaneous printed matter (Folder 12)
  - Filippov, Boris
    - Correspondence
      - Struve, Gleb
        - 1952-1954 (Folder 13)
        - 1955-1959 (Folder 14)
        - 1960-1961 (Folder 15)
        - 1962 (Box 84, Folder 1)
        - 1963-1964 (Folder 2)
        - 1965 (Folder 3)
        - 1966 (Folder 4)
        - 1967-1968 (Folder 5)
        - 1969 (Folder 6)
        - 1970-1971 (Folder 7)
        - 1972-1976 (Folder 8)
        - 1976-1979 (Folder 9)
        - 1980-1985 (Folder 10)
      - Struve, Nikita, 1966-1981 (Folder 11)
    - Writings
      - "'Pogorel'shchina' Nikolaia Kliueva", Estratto da: "Studi in onore di Ettore Lo Gatto e Giovanni Maver", 1962, printed copy (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - "Liki Rossii v russkoi poezii. Antologiia russkoi poezii, 1917-1958", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 2)
      - "Zametki ob Anne Akhmatovoi", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1956-1985 (Folder 4-6)
  - Fitz Lyon, Kyrill. See Zinoviev, Kirill
  - Frank, Viktor
    - Correspondence between Viktor Frank and Gleb Struve
      - 1938-1949 (Folder 7)
      - 1950-1971 (Folder 8)
    - Writings, miscellaneous, printed copies, 1947-1949 (Folder 9)
  - Galich, Leonid. Clippings, 1946-1961 (Folder 10)
  - Gazeta-Protest, Nov. 26, 1917, typescript and photocopies (Folder 11)
  - Gendlin, Leonid
    - Correspondence between Leonid Gendlin and Gleb Struve, 1972-1973 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1972-1982 (Folder 2)
  - Gertsyk, Adelaida, "A dusha poet, posmertnaia kniga, 1911-1925", Moskva, 1978, typescript copy (Folder 3)
  - Gippius, Zinaida. Printed matter
    - Scholarly articles, reprints, 1960-1961 (Folder 4)
    - Clippings from newspapers, 1926-1972 (Folder 5)
  - Glazov, Iurii. Letter to the editor of an unidentified newspaper, typescript draft, 1978(?) (Folder 6)
  - Gogol', Nikolai. Printed matter
    - Scholarly articles, reprints, 1951-1980 (Folder 7)
    - Clippings from newspapers, 1934-1958 (Folder 8)
  - Goncharova, Natalia
    - Popova, Vera, "Moi vospominaniia o teatral'noi rabote s Natal'eii Sergeevnoi Goncharovoi", typescript draft, 1966 (Folder 9)
    - Clipping of obituary, 1962 (Folder 10)
  - Grot, Elena. Clippings, 1949-1976 (Folder 11)
  - Grani. Clippings, 1952-1985 (Folder 12)
  - Gumilev, Lev. Miscellaneous printed matter, 1964-1976 (Folder 13)
  - Gumilev, Nikolai
    - Biographical material
      - General
        - Amfiteatrov, Aleksandr
          - Miscellaneous articles re last days and death of Nikolai Gumilev published in newspaper Segodnia, photocopies, 1931 (Folder 14)
          - "Gorestnye Zametki. Ocherki krasnogo Petrograda", Grani, Berlin, 1922, photocopy (Folder 15)
        - Golinkov, David, Krushenie antisovetskogo podpol'ia v S.S.S.R., Politizdat, Moscow, photocopies (Folder 16)
        - "Materialy k istorii otnoshenii N.S. Gumileva s E.I. Dmitrievoi (Cherubinoi de Gabriak)", typescript, n.d. (Folder 17)
        - Miscellaneous material, clippings and typescript copies, 1924-1979 (Folder 18)
      - Reminiscences re Nikolai Gumilev
        - Kliuev, Literaturnye vstrechi, Moscow, 1958, typescript excerpt re Nikolai Gumilev (Folder 19)
        - Mochalova, Ol'ga, "Navsegda", Moscow, 1971, typescript copy (Folder 20)
        - "Vospominaniia V. Sreznevskoi", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 21)
        - Unknown author, "Nikolai Gumilev", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 22)
        - Miscellaneous material, clippings and typescript copies, 1925-1980 (Folder 23)
      - Personal documents
        - Miscellaneous. Includes petition to Rector of St. Petersburg University re marriage to A. A. Goren'ko, typescript and photocopies, 1910-1917 (Folder 24)
        - Military Service Record, (posluzhnoi spisok), Dec. 1916. Photocopy. Original in Restricted Series (Folder 25)
        - Certificate no. 2082. Payments made by Quartemaster General of Russian Expeditionary Force in France to Nikolai Gumilev, Paris, Jan. 1918. Photocopy. Original in Restricted Series (Folder 26)
        - "Memoire concernant une possibilite eventuelle d'un recrutement de contingents de volontaires pour L'Armee Francaise en Abyssinie", n.d. Photocopy. Original in Restricted Series (Folder 27)
        - Letter from Gumilev to Representative of Provisional Government requesting transfer to Persian Front, Jan. 1918. Photocopy. Original in Restricted Series (Folder 28)
        - Documents relating to Gumilev's mission to London. Photocopies. Originals in Restricted Series
          - Official orders for mission
            - Jan. 3/16, 1918, in Russian (Folder 29)
            - Jan. 20, 1918, in French (Folder 30)
          - Certificate of payment of salary and travel expenses. Stamped "Attache Militaire de Russie a Londres", Jan. 1918 (Folder 31)
          - Russian Military Agent in Great Britain
            - Letter informing Gumilev of arrival of correspondence from Paris, Feb. 5/ Jan. 23, 1918 (Folder 32)
            - Official request for personal information, signed Balashov, Feb. 21, 1918 (Folder 33)
          - Notebook containing notes, addresses, appointments, 1918 (Folder 34)
          - Bill from Turner's Hotel, April 1918 (Folder 35)
        - Agreement with publisher Krestin, 1919, typescript copy (Folder 36)
        - Petition of A. I. Gumileva to Writer's Union of Petrograd, 1921, typescript copy (Folder 37)
    - Correspondence of Nikolai Gumilev
      - General. Typescript and handwritten copies of originals in Ts.G.A.L.I. Includes correspondence of Annenskii, Bugaev, Briusov and V. Ivanov, 1909-1918 (Folder 38)
      - Akhmatova, Anna, 1912-1915. Published in Amanda Haight, "Letters From Nikolay Gumilyov to Anna Akhmatova 1912-1915", printed copy of article and photocopy of excerpts, n.d. (Folder 39)
      - Briusov, Valerii, 1907-1912. Also includes correspondence with Mikhail Kuz'min, Fedor Sologub and others, typescript, 1910-1920 (Box 87, Folder 1)
      - Crozat, J. Letter to Nikolai Gumilev, 1917, original and typescript copy (Folder 2)
      - L'dov, K. (Folder 3)
        - Verse, 1917
        - Letter, 1918
      - Reisner, Larisa, 1916-1917. Typescript and photocopies of published letters. Includes footnotes by Gleb Struve (Folder 4)
    - Correspondence relating to Nikolai Gumilev
      - General, 1965-1968 (Folder 5)
      - Arundel del Rey, letters of introduction for Gumilev's trip to Italy, typescript copies, n.d. (Holograph of letters in personal notebook of Nikolai Gumilev. See documents) (Folder 6)
      - Toussaint, letter to Mikhail Lario nov, 1917 (Folder 7)
      - Tsitron, Aleksandr. Letters to Mikhail Larionov (Folder 8)
        - 1919, copy
        - 1927
        - Letter to the editor of Poslednie Novosti, n.d.
      - Miscellaneous material re Nikolai Gumilev's correspondence. Includes typescript and photocopies of letters, lists of correspondence, n.d. (Folder 9)
    - Writings
      - Poetry
        - Chuzhoe nebo, tret'ia kniga stikhov, Izdanie "Apollona", St.Petersburg 1912, photocopy (Folder 10)
        - "Gondla", variant of Act I, scene 1, typescript copy of original in Ts.G.A.L.I., n.d. (Folder 11)
        - Koster
          - First edition. Izdanie Giperborei, St. Petersburg, 1918, photocopy (Folder 12)
          - Second edition. Z.J. Grshebin, Verlag, Berlin, 1922, photocopy (Folder 13)
        - Mik, afrikanskaia poema
          - First edition. Izdatel'stvo Giperborei, St. Petersburg, 1918, photocopy (Folder 14)
          - Second edition. "Mysl'", Petrograd, 1922 (Folder 15)
        - "Mik i Lui", Niva, No. 4, Feb. 1917, galley proof. Photocopy. Original in Restricted Series (Folder 16)
        - Notebook containing four poems in French, n.d. Holograph (photocopy). Original in Restricted Series (Folder 17)
        - Otravlennaia tunika
          - Knigoizdatel'stvo "Svecha", Paris, 1934. Copy received from S.K. Makovskii in 1953 (Folder 18)
          - Personal copy of Lollii L'vov, typescript, 1941 (?) (Folder 19)
          - "Tragediia v piati eistviiakh", Paris, London, Spring 1917, Winter 1918. Holograph (photocopy). Original in Restricted Series (Folder 20)
          - Beginning of fair copy, n.d. Holograph (photocopy). Original in Restricted Series (Folder 21)
          - Stage directions, n.d. Holograph (photocopy). Original in Restricted Series (Folder 22)
        - Put' konkvistadorov, Tipo.-Lit. R.S. Vol'pina, St. Petersburg, 1905, photocopy (Folder 23)
        - Romanticheskie tsvety, stikhi, 1903-1907
          - First edition, Paris, 1908, photocopy (Folder 24)
          - Second edition, kn. vo. Prometei N.N. Mikhailova, St. Petersburg, 1918, photocopy (Folder 25)
        - "Sentimental'noe stikhotvorenie dlia T.M. Devich". Single sheet, includes two versions of poem, one dated 15/25/I/05, the other dated 15/17/I/05. Holograph (photocopy). Original in Restricted Series (Folder 26)
        - "Stikhi". Notebook containing 80 poems. Illustrated by Dimitrii Stelletskii and Natalia Goncharova, 1916. Holograph (photocopy). Original in Restricted Series. See Audio-Visual File for slides (Folder 27)
        - "Stikhi prilozhennye k pis'mam k Briusovu", typescript, n.d. (Folder 28)
        - Stikhotvoreniia, posmertnyi sbornik, Tsentral'noe Kooperativnoe Izdatel'stvo "Mysl'", Petrograd, 1922 (Box 88, Folder 1)
        - Stikhotvoreniia, posmertnyi sbornik, vtoroe dopolnitel'noe izdanie, Tsentral'noe Kooperativnoe Izdatel'stvo "Mysl'", Petrograd, 1923 (Folder 2)
        - Zhemchuga, Knigoizdatel'stvo "Skorpion", Moscow, 1910 (Folder 3)
        - Photocopies and typescripts, miscellaneous poetry, 1908-1923 (Folder 4)
      - Prose
        - "Chernyi Dik", Rech', May 15, 1908, photocopy (Folder 5)
        - "Chernyi general", July 1917, photocopy (Folder 6)
        - "Gibeli obrechennye", typescript and photocopy copy, n.d. (Folder 7)
        - "Karty" and "Vverkh po Nilu", typescript copy, n.d. (Folder 8)
        - "Lesnoi d'iavol", handwritten copy, n.d. (Folder 9)
        - "Po povodu 'salona' Makovskogo", 1908, handwritten copy (Folder 10)
        - "Umer li Menelik?", Niva No. 5, 1914, photocopy (Folder 11)
        - "Veselye brat'ia"
          - Single sheets, n.d. Holograph (photocopy). Originals in Restricted Series (Folder 12)
          - Beginning of fair copy, n.d. Holograph (photocopy). Original in Restricted Series (Folder 13)
        - "Zapiski kavalerista", Birzhevye Vedomosti, Feb. 3, 1915-Jan. ll, 1916, photocopy (Folder 14)
        - Miscellaneous single sheets, n.d. Holograph (photocopies). Originals in Restricted Series. Includes outline of article on poetry and outline for short story (?) (Folder 15)
      - Criticism
        - "Kriticheskie stat'i, ne voshedshie v chetyrekhtomnik", review of M.Kuz'min, Osenie ozera. Vtoraia kniga stikhov, M. Izd. "Skorpion", 1912, typescript copy (Folder 16)
        - "Pis'mo o russkoi poezii", Apollon, photocopy, n.d. (Folder 17)
        - "Zhizn' stikha", photocopy, n.d. (Folder 18)
        - Miscellaneous photocopies and clippings, 1908-1909 (Folder 19)
      - Translations by Nikolai Gumilev, photocopies
        - Ballady. Robert Southey's ballads translated and edited by Nikolai Gumilev. Gosudarstvennoe Izdatel'stvo, Petersburg, 1922 (Folder 20)
        - Ballady o Robin Gude. Edited and translated by Nikolai Gumilev, with a foreword by Maksim Gorkii. Izdatel'stvo "Vsemirnaia Literatura", Petersburg, 1919 (Folder 21)
        - Kaval'kada Izol'dy. F. Viele- Grifen, Severnye Zapiski, n.d. (Folder 22)
        - Pippa prokhodit. Robert Browning, Severnyie Zapiski, 1914, photocopy (Folder 23)
        - Poema o starom moriake. S. Coleridge's, Rhyme of the Ancient Mariner
          - Izdatel'stvo "Vsemirnaia Literatura", Petersburg, 1919. Introduction (Folder 24)
          - Photocopy of published text and typescript, 1926 (Folder 25)
    - Periodicals containing writings by Gumilev, photocopies
      - Apollon, Nos. 7, 9, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - "Sirius", Nos. 1, 2, 3, 1910 (Folder 2)
      - Vesy, No. 6, n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Translations of Gumilev's work, typescript, photocopies and handwritten copies, n.d. (Folder 4)
    - Drawings
      - Photocopies. Originals in Restricted Series
        - Cocteau, Jean (?). Small portrait in ink of Pablo Picasso. Sent by Cocteau to Gumilev in Paris, 1916 (Folder 5)
        - Gumilev, Nikolai. Two small pencil drawings, n.d. (Folder 6)
        - Larionov, Mikhail. Two small pencil portraits of Gumilev in uniform, n.d. (Folder 7)
        - Stelletskii, Dimitrii. Self-portrait (?) Drawing in ink with autograph, n.d. (Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous drawings by Gumilev, photocopies, 1921 (Folder 9)
    - Critical essays and reviews of Nikolai Gumilev's work
      - Acmeism, miscellaneous photocopies (Folder 10)
      - Aikhenval'd, Iu., "Gumilev", typescript, n.d. (Folder 11)
      - Chulkov, G., "Poet-Voin", typescript copy of original in G.B.R.L.O., 1916? (Folder 12)
      - Graham, Sheelagh
        - "N.S. Gumilev and the Irish Legend. Unpublished Fragment From The Beauty of Morni", Irish Slavonic Studies, No. 5, 1984. Photocopy (Folder 13)
        - "Unpublished Letters From Gumilev to Bryusov, 1906-1907", SEER, Vol. 61, No. 4, Oct. 1983. Typescript draft and reprint (Folder 14)
      - Lunts, Lev, "Tsekh poetov", printed copy, n.d. (Folder 15)
      - L'vov, Lollii, "Otravlennaia tunika Gumileva", typescript, n.d. (Folder 16)
      - Mochul'skii, Konstantin, "Klassitsyzm v sovremennoi russkoi poezii", photocopy, n.d. (Folder 17)
      - Sechkarev, Vsevolod, "Gumilev dramaturg", typescript, n.d. (Folder 18)
      - Timenchik, R. D., Zametki ob akmeizme, photocopy, n.d. (Folder 19)
      - Reviews of Gumilev's work in periodical press, typescript and photocopies, 1908-1982 (Folder 20-21)
    - Bibliography
      - Lists of Nikolai Gumilev material found in Soviet archives, n.d. (Folder 22)
      - Pereleshin, Valerii, "K bibliografii Gumileva", Russian Language Journal, No. 86, 1970, typescript copy (Folder 23)
    - Ts.G.A.L.I., miscellaneous material, typescript and photocopies, n.d. (Folder 24)
    - Clippings, 1920-1985 (Folder 25)
  - Harbin poets
    - Rachinskaia, E., "Zamolknuvshye golosa. O kharbinskikh poetakh", Novoye Russkoye Slovo, Jan. 14, 1959, printed copy (Folder 26)
    - Sentianina, E., "Kharbinskie pisateli i poety", typescript draft, n.d. (Folder 27)
  - Il'in, Ivan
    - Correspondence between Ivan Il'in and Gleb Struve, 1959 (Folder 28)
    - Clippings of articles by Ivan Il'in, 1923-1935 (Folder 29)
  - International Comparative Literature Association II Congress, the University of North Carolina, Sept. 1958. Programs, newspaper clippings, membership lists (Folder 30)
  - International Federation for Modern Languages and Literatures
    - VII Congress, Heidelberg, 1957. Programs, correspondence, miscellaneous material (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - X International Congress, 1966. Program (Folder 2)
    - XII International Conference, Cambridge University, 1972. Programs and miscellaneous material (Folder 3)
  - International Symposium On Soviet Literature In the Sixties, Munich, 1963
    - Official information. Includes list of participants and program, typescript (Folder 4)
    - "Notes On Discussion", typescript pamphlet (Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous material. Typescript and handwritten notes, n.d. (Folder 6)
    - Papers delivered at conference, typescript copies
      - Adamovich, Anthony, "Current Trends In the Non-Russian Soviet Literatures" (Folder 7)